<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michelle Plunkett</title>
    <description>This is Michelle Plunkett&#39;s website.
</description>
    <link>http://michelle-plunkett.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://michelle-plunkett.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 20:51:38 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 20:51:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome!</title>
        <description>Welcome to my brand new website!

&lt;h4&gt;–Michelle&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 09:35:24 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://michelle-plunkett.com/posts/2015/07/29/welcome.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://michelle-plunkett.com/posts/2015/07/29/welcome.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Test 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Location:&lt;/b&gt; Test 2&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;b&gt;Information:&lt;/b&gt; Test 2&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Test post 2.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 18:46:52 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://michelle-plunkett.com/reflections/2015/07/28/test-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://michelle-plunkett.com/reflections/2015/07/28/test-2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>reflections</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cultural and Social Trends and the Affect on Krannert Center</title>
        <description>				&lt;p&gt;The prices increased because the people who chose to continue to support the &quot;high&quot; arts had to accept higher prices in order to maintain the supply of the art that they preferred. This was also when the new model for arts organizations began to develop. Nonprofit arts organizations were now a way for people to distinguish themselves in society through their tastes in art.&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;I believe that the Krannert Center (opened in 1969) was most affected by the Ford Foundation movement in the 1950s. The creation of Krannert allowed Central Illinois to be a highly functioning supporter of the &quot;high&quot; arts by providing a regional destination for artists previously based of out NYC or other metropolitan areas. However, I do think that Krannert was affected by the split between &quot;high&quot; arts and &quot;popular&quot; arts. This is seen through the gradual rise in prices despite the &quot;high&quot; arts growth throughout the second half of the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt; 
				
				&lt;p&gt;For example, the price of admission for a UI Student for the &quot;Dedication Concert&quot; at Krannert on April 19, 1969 was $1.50 and $2.50 for the general public which can be seen in the picture below (Dedication Concert Tickets, 1969). With inflation accounted for (by using an inflation calculator), the price would still only be $9.67 if a similar UI Student ticket was sold today. This is especially remarkable because this is almost the current price of a UI Student ticket, which is $10 for most events and concerts. The dedication of Krannert to maintain a low cost of admission for current UI Students is unmatched.&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;However, not only was this the dedication concert held to open Krannert officially, but the concert featured famous musicians like Tossy Spivakovsky (a virtuoso violinist). Spivakovsky, most likely, was not cheap to hire even in the 1960s. So it is impressive that the cost was still low to attend the dedication even when renowned artists were invited to perform.&lt;p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;    
				  
				&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/discussion1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;    
				  
				&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;However, nowadays, a ticket to attend a concert at Krannert at the same magnitude of the 1969 dedication concert will set an adult back around $50 today ($7.76 in 1969). So, the cost of a ticket to attend a comparable event at Krannert today is around 3 times more expensive ($7.76 divided by $2.50) than when Krannert first opened. The price increase is very clear when put in this context. However, it is worth noting that the price could have been lower for the Dedication Concert through the support of sponsor funding and from Mr. and Mrs. Krannert&#39;s direct contribution. But I think the price increase seen in this example is still relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;I think that the Krannert Center for the Performing Arts presents a combination of popular arts and high arts. Krannert features classical music from world-renown symphonies and orchestras while also embracing a popular music culture. Popular music can be seen at the biyearly guitar festival held at Krannert called ELLNORA. Artists that are not considered to be &quot;high&quot; art can be seen at this festival like the Punch Brothers and Bela Fleck. (Speaking of which, ELLNORA is named after Mrs. Krannert, whose first name is Ellnora.) However, during the August-May school year, I do think mostly &quot;high&quot; art like classical music concerts are featured, especially since our own School of Music uses Foellinger Great Hall almost exclusively for major ensemble concerts.&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a bonus picture of the construction on Krannert&#39;s Great Hall, just because I think it is super cool and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;    
				  
				&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/discussion2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;    
				  
				&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;By the way, for anyone who is wondering, I received these pictures and information about Krannert from the UIUC Archives while I was doing research for RHET 105 (a freshman writing course). There is a scrapbook currently held in the UIUC Undergrad Library Archives that contains all of the newspaper clippings and items (like the tickets I feature in this post) from the grand opening of Krannert. I would highly suggest checking it out if you have some free time!&lt;/p&gt; 
				
				&lt;p&gt;    
				  
				&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;center&gt;References&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;Dedication Concert Tickets, (April 19-20, 1969), Record Series 32/1/12, Box 2, University of Illinois Archives.&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;Krannert Center Great Hall Construction, 1968, Photographic Subject File, Record Series 39/2/20, Box BUI – KCPA, Folder BUI – KCPA Construction Great Hall 1968, University of Illinois Archives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://michelle-plunkett.com/discussions/2015/06/22/discussion2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://michelle-plunkett.com/discussions/2015/06/22/discussion2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>discussions</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cultural and Social Trends and the Affect on Krannert Center</title>
        <description>				&lt;p&gt;As found in the Ziff Marketing, Inc. survey mentioned in Chapter 4 of &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration:underline;&quot;&gt;Management and the Arts&lt;/span&gt;, I think that Krannert&#39;s attendance is largely affected by peer group influence. When I have asked my older coworkers why they attended a certain show at Krannert, many of them will say, &quot;because my friend invited me,&quot; or because their friend told them about the show and recommended it to them. I have found in my own experience that people who did not &quot;grow up&quot; in the arts like most music students, like myself, find their way into the arts through being invited to an event.&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s why I think the events that Krannert is now holding after certain events to meet the musicians is very important to grow audiences. Events like the meet and greets that were held last season make the musicians and performers more accessible to people who have previously not had that much exposure to classical music or  the theatre.  I think part of the reason these events are so successful is the social accessibility of audience members to the performers. If an audience member was invited to attend an event at Krannert with a meet and greet scheduled to occur right after the event concludes, I think they will be more likely to attend another show or concert at Krannert in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;In terms of other social factors, I think the Champaign-Urbana community is a relatively &quot;open-minded&quot; community with a more liberal mindset. This can be seen through a number of non-traditional events that Krannert holds every year. Champaign-Urbana also is open and accepting to the gay community, offering gay bars like &quot;C-Street&quot; and other accepting events held in the community. This being said, I do not think Krannert is affected by any particularly negative social trends and is accepting of homosexuals and not repressed by religious beliefs within the community.&lt;/p&gt;
				
				&lt;p&gt;Overall, I do not think any major cultural or social trends affect Krannert&#39;s programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://michelle-plunkett.com/discussions/2015/06/22/discussion1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://michelle-plunkett.com/discussions/2015/06/22/discussion1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>discussions</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Analysis of Krannert Center&#39;s Mission &amp; Vision</title>
        <description>							&lt;b&gt;Krannert Center Mission &amp; Vision:&lt;/b&gt;
							&lt;ul&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Krannert Center for the Performing Arts is dedicated to the advancement of education, research, and public engagement through the pursuit of excellence and innovation in the performing arts.&lt;/li&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Embracing the art of the past as well as the art of our time, the Center supports the belief that creativity is a core human characteristic and that the arts hold uniquely transformativepotential.&lt;/li&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Through its multiple and integrated roles as classroom, laboratory, and public square, KrannertCenter serves as a touchstone for the exploration and expansion of human experience.&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;/ul&gt;
							&lt;p&gt;I think Krannert&#39;s website presents very clear and concise mission and vision statements. Not only are the statements clear, but the statements are presented on their website in such a way that it is very easy to find. The mission and vision statements are logically located under the &quot;Meet Us&quot; portion of the homepage and then located within the &quot;Mission and Vision&quot; subpage.&lt;/p&gt;
							
							&lt;p&gt;I find it fitting that Krannert employees put the mission and vision statements within the &quot;Meet Us&quot; section of the website. Because that is what mission and vision statements should do. Consumers should be able to theoretically &quot;meet&quot; the business and learn what the organization is setting out to do through reading these statements.&lt;/p&gt;
							
							&lt;p&gt;My only suggestion to make this subpage on Krannert&#39;s website more effective and visible to a consumer is to hyperlink to the mission subpage through other pages that mention something having to do with working towards the vision/mission. For example, the mission and vision page could behyperlinked within the &quot;Volunteer&quot; subpage in order to increase a potential volunteer&#39;s awareness of the true values that Krannert has in their everyday business and to become a more informed consumer. The knowledge gained by a volunteer from understanding Krannert&#39;s mission would trickle down the ladder through their conversations with patrons and other community members during their shifts, for example. This could potentially influence attendance by a patron in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
							
							&lt;p&gt;However, I do not believe that the statements need to be rewritten. I do think there is always room for improvement involving clarity and syntax, but in its current state, I think the statements present a clear and accurate goal set that Krannert has set forth to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://michelle-plunkett.com/blogs/2015/06/22/blog1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://michelle-plunkett.com/blogs/2015/06/22/blog1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blogs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RAND Corporations Report (2001): A Response</title>
        <description>							&lt;p&gt;Other developing trends that have occurred in the field since the report was published include the trends in technology and how it affects the online presence of an arts organization. The Internet was still just developing to be the massive system that it is now in the late 1990s and the early 2000s, around when this report was published. The developing Internet trend was discussed briefly in the summary section of the reading but I think it is worth discussing in greater detail since the growth has been so large. I think that since the early 2000s, the development of social media and the availability of technology to consumers has affected the growth of the performing arts and entertainment fields.&lt;/p&gt;
							
							&lt;p&gt;Marketing for performing arts organizations, through the aid of social media on the Internet, now has an audience of more than just people that live near the arts center or organization. I believe that through social media, new and larger audiences in more than one location have been created. This can especially be seen with Twitter. A consumer can follow the daily doings and happenings at the Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, or even our very own Krannert Center from the comfort of their own home thousands of miles away from New York City or Urbana.&lt;/p&gt;
							
							&lt;p&gt;Not only can a consumer follow a performing arts center on Twitter, but they can directly contact the arts center through this medium. This means they potentially have the ability to affect what is performed or things that the consumer would like to see happen at the arts organization. Also, the arts center has the ability now to receive direct, unfiltered, feedback from consumers in real-time. The trends in social media are affecting the performing arts and entertainment field by allowing the consumer to have more control over how they spend their money.&lt;/p&gt;
							
							&lt;p&gt;I think it would be cool for more arts organizations to have applications on mobile devices. I think the use of mobile technology is limited right now in the arts industry, and I think they are missing out on a opportunity to advertise performances even more to new audiences. For example, the Starbucks app knows when you are near a Starbucks through GPS locating. A performing arts center application could notify someone when they are near the arts center and send them a small list of upcoming performances with a link to buy tickets. Real-time advertising like notifications could affect the audience demographics drastically.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://michelle-plunkett.com/blogs/2015/06/16/blog2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://michelle-plunkett.com/blogs/2015/06/16/blog2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blogs</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
